[
    {
        "answer": "DC Comics",
        "question": "Who publishes the comics of Alexander Joseph Luthor?",
        "sentence": "\nAlexander Joseph Luthor ( or ) is a fictional supervillain appearing in American comic books published by DC Comics ."
    },
    {
        "answer": "Alexander Joseph Luthor",
        "question": "Who is a fictional supervillain in comic books?",
        "sentence": "\nAlexander Joseph Luthor ( or ) is a fictional supervillain appearing in American comic books published by DC Comics ."
    },
    {
        "answer": "Action Comics No",
        "question": "Where did Lex Luthor first appear?",
        "sentence": "Lex Luthor originally appeared in Action Comics No ."
    },
    {
        "answer": "Lex Luthor",
        "question": "What character first appeared in Action Comics No?",
        "sentence": "Lex Luthor originally appeared in Action Comics No ."
    },
    {
        "answer": "Action Comics No",
        "question": "Where did Lex Luthor first appear?",
        "sentence": "Lex Luthor originally appeared in Action Comics No ."
    },
    {
        "answer": "Superman",
        "question": "He has endured as the archenemy of what superhero?",
        "sentence": "He has since endured as the archenemy of Superman ."
    },
    {
        "answer": "narcissistic and egotistical mad scientist",
        "question": "What was Lex Luthor originally depicted as?",
        "sentence": "Lex Luthor was originally depicted as a narcissistic and egotistical mad scientist , but since the late 1980s , he has more often been portrayed as a power - mad business magnate , the CEO of LexCorp ."
    },
    {
        "answer": "LexCorp",
        "question": "What company is Lex Luthor CEO of?",
        "sentence": "Lex Luthor was originally depicted as a narcissistic and egotistical mad scientist , but since the late 1980s , he has more often been portrayed as a power - mad business magnate , the CEO of LexCorp ."
    },
    {
        "answer": "a threat to humanity",
        "question": "Why does he want to rid the world of Superman?",
        "sentence": "He wishes to rid the world of Superman , ostensibly because he views Superman as a threat to humanity , but in reality envies Superman 's popularity and influence ."
    },
    {
        "answer": "Batman",
        "question": "Along with other superheroes in the DC Universe, who has he often clashed with?",
        "sentence": "Given his high profile as a supervillain , however , he has often come into conflict with Batman and other superheroes in the DC Universe ."
    },
    {
        "answer": "Lex Luthor",
        "question": "Who wears a Warsuit?",
        "sentence": "Lex Luthor is an ordinary human and has no natural superpowers but occasionally wears his Warsuit , a suit of mechanized armor that gives him enhanced strength , flight , advanced weaponry , and other capabilities ."
    },
    {
        "answer": "Superman",
        "question": "Lex has been portrayed as an antihero who will ally himself with whom?",
        "sentence": "While Lex is primarily depicted as a supervillain allied with other villains in the likes of Metallo , Parasite and Bizarro , and frequently leading DC supervillain teams such as the Legion of Doom , he has also been portrayed as an antihero who will ally himself with Superman and other heroes when situation calls for it ."
    },
    {
        "answer": "Legion of Doom",
        "question": "What DC supervillain team does Lex lead?",
        "sentence": "While Lex is primarily depicted as a supervillain allied with other villains in the likes of Metallo , Parasite and Bizarro , and frequently leading DC supervillain teams such as the Legion of Doom , he has also been portrayed as an antihero who will ally himself with Superman and other heroes when situation calls for it ."
    },
    {
        "answer": "8th",
        "question": "Where did the character rank on Wizard's 100 Greatest Villains of All Time list?",
        "sentence": "The character was ranked 4th on IGN 's list of the Top 100 Comic Book Villains of All Time and as the 8th Greatest Villain by Wizard on its 100 Greatest Villains of All Time list ."
    },
    {
        "answer": "Wizard",
        "question": "Who ranked the character 8th Greatest Villain on IGN's 100 Greatest Villains of All Time list?",
        "sentence": "The character was ranked 4th on IGN 's list of the Top 100 Comic Book Villains of All Time and as the 8th Greatest Villain by Wizard on its 100 Greatest Villains of All Time list ."
    },
    {
        "answer": "4th",
        "question": "Where did the character rank on IGN's list of the Top 100 Comic Book Villains of All Time?",
        "sentence": "The character was ranked 4th on IGN 's list of the Top 100 Comic Book Villains of All Time and as the 8th Greatest Villain by Wizard on its 100 Greatest Villains of All Time list ."
    },
    {
        "answer": "Luthor",
        "question": "What is one of a few genre - crossing villains whose adventures take place \"in a world where the ordinary laws of nature are slightly",
        "sentence": "Luthor is one of a few genre - crossing villains whose adventures take place \" in a world in which the ordinary laws of nature are slightly suspended \" ."
    },
    {
        "answer": "films",
        "question": "Lyle Talbot, Gene Hackman, Kevin Spacey, and Jesse Eisenberg have portrayed the character in what?",
        "sentence": "Scott James Wells , Sherman Howard , John Shea , Michael Rosenbaum and Jon Cryer have portrayed the character in television series , while Lyle Talbot , Gene Hackman , Kevin Spacey , and Jesse Eisenberg have portrayed the character in films ."
    },
    {
        "answer": "Scott James Wells",
        "question": "Who has portrayed the character in television series?",
        "sentence": "Scott James Wells , Sherman Howard , John Shea , Michael Rosenbaum and Jon Cryer have portrayed the character in television series , while Lyle Talbot , Gene Hackman , Kevin Spacey , and Jesse Eisenberg have portrayed the character in films ."
    },
    {
        "answer": "Clancy Brown",
        "question": "Which actor has provided Luthor's voice in animated films?",
        "sentence": "Several actors have provided Luthor 's voice in animated adaptations , including Clancy Brown , Mark Rolston , James Marsters and Giancarlo Esposito ."
    },
    {
        "answer": "Action Comics No",
        "question": "What was the name of his first story?",
        "sentence": "In his first story appearance , Action Comics No ."
    },
    {
        "answer": "Action Comics No",
        "question": "What was the name of his first story?",
        "sentence": "In his first story appearance , Action Comics No ."
    },
    {
        "answer": "23",
        "question": "How old was Luthor when he was born?",
        "sentence": "23 ( April 1940 ) , Luthor is depicted as a diabolical genius and is referred to only by his surname ."
    },
    {
        "answer": "his surname",
        "question": "What is Luthor only referred to by?",
        "sentence": "23 ( April 1940 ) , Luthor is depicted as a diabolical genius and is referred to only by his surname ."
    },
    {
        "answer": "a dirigible",
        "question": "What is suspended in the city?",
        "sentence": "He resides in a flying city suspended by a dirigible and plots to provoke a war between two European nations ."
    },
    {
        "answer": "a flying city",
        "question": "Where does he live?",
        "sentence": "He resides in a flying city suspended by a dirigible and plots to provoke a war between two European nations ."
    },
    {
        "answer": "Luthor",
        "question": "Who fights Superman with a green ray?",
        "sentence": "Luthor battles Superman with a green ray but he is ultimately defeated , and Lois is rescued ."
    },
    {
        "answer": "Lois",
        "question": "Who is rescued?",
        "sentence": "Luthor battles Superman with a green ray but he is ultimately defeated , and Lois is rescued ."
    },
    {
        "answer": "Superman",
        "question": "Who destroys Luthor's dirigible with him still on it?",
        "sentence": "Superman destroys Luthor 's dirigible with him still on it , implying Luthor may have died ."
    },
    {
        "answer": "Luthor",
        "question": "Whose dirigible does Superman destroy with him still on it?",
        "sentence": "Superman destroys Luthor 's dirigible with him still on it , implying Luthor may have died ."
    },
    {
        "answer": "Luthor",
        "question": "Whose death became common in his earliest appearances?",
        "sentence": "Stories ending with Luthor 's apparent death become common in his earliest appearances , with him turning up alive later on ."
    },
    {
        "answer": "Luthor",
        "question": "Who returns in Superman No?",
        "sentence": "Luthor returns in Superman No ."
    },
    {
        "answer": "Superman No",
        "question": "What is the name of Luthor's next movie?",
        "sentence": "Luthor returns in Superman No ."
    },
    {
        "answer": "Superman No",
        "question": "What is the name of Luthor's next movie?",
        "sentence": "Luthor returns in Superman No ."
    },
    {
        "answer": "Luthor",
        "question": "Who does Superman defeat?",
        "sentence": "Superman battles and defeats Luthor , then destroys the earthquake device ."
    },
    {
        "answer": "Superman",
        "question": "Who defeats Luthor?",
        "sentence": "Superman battles and defeats Luthor , then destroys the earthquake device ."
    },
    {
        "answer": "Luthor",
        "question": "Who creates a city on the Lost continent of Pacifo?",
        "sentence": "In a story in the same issue , Luthor creates a city on the sunken Lost continent of Pacifo and populates it with recreated prehistoric monsters he plans to unleash upon the world ."
    },
    {
        "answer": "Lost continent of Pacifo",
        "question": "Where is Luthor's city located?",
        "sentence": "In a story in the same issue , Luthor creates a city on the sunken Lost continent of Pacifo and populates it with recreated prehistoric monsters he plans to unleash upon the world ."
    },
    {
        "answer": "Luthor",
        "question": "Who is killed by the dinosaurs he created?",
        "sentence": "Superman thwarts his plans and Luthor is seemingly killed by the dinosaurs he created ."
    },
    {
        "answer": "dinosaurs",
        "question": "Who kills Luthor?",
        "sentence": "Superman thwarts his plans and Luthor is seemingly killed by the dinosaurs he created ."
    },
    {
        "answer": "Luthor",
        "question": "Who returns in Superman No?",
        "sentence": "Luthor returns in Superman No ."
    },
    {
        "answer": "Superman No",
        "question": "What is the name of Luthor's next movie?",
        "sentence": "Luthor returns in Superman No ."
    },
    {
        "answer": "Superman No",
        "question": "What is the name of Luthor's next movie?",
        "sentence": "Luthor returns in Superman No ."
    },
    {
        "answer": "hypnotic gas",
        "question": "What is the plan to place in the offices of influential people?",
        "sentence": "5 with a plan to place hypnotic gas in the offices of influential people so he can throw the nation into a depression with the help of corrupt financier Moseley ."
    },
    {
        "answer": "Moseley",
        "question": "Who is a corrupt financier?",
        "sentence": "5 with a plan to place hypnotic gas in the offices of influential people so he can throw the nation into a depression with the help of corrupt financier Moseley ."
    },
    {
        "answer": "Superman",
        "question": "Who defeats Superman?",
        "sentence": "The story ends with Superman defeating him ."
    },
    {
        "answer": "Luthor",
        "question": "Whose hatred of Superman came later in the character's development?",
        "sentence": "Luthor 's obsessive hatred of Superman came later in the character 's development ."
    },
    {
        "answer": "obsessive hatred of Superman",
        "question": "What was Luthor's reaction to Superman?",
        "sentence": "Luthor 's obsessive hatred of Superman came later in the character 's development ."
    },
    {
        "answer": "red hair",
        "question": "What color hair does Luthor have?",
        "sentence": "In Luthor 's earliest appearances , he is shown as a middle - aged man with a full head of red hair ."
    },
    {
        "answer": "middle - aged",
        "question": "What age is Luthor in his earliest appearances?",
        "sentence": "In Luthor 's earliest appearances , he is shown as a middle - aged man with a full head of red hair ."
    },
    {
        "answer": "bald",
        "question": "What was Luthor depicted as in a newspaper strip?",
        "sentence": "Less than a year later , however , an artistic mistake resulted in Luthor being depicted as completely bald in a newspaper strip ."
    },
    {
        "answer": "balding",
        "question": "What did Luthor look like in his Golden Age incarnation?",
        "sentence": "One hypothesis is that Nowak mistook Luthor for the Ultra - Humanite , a recurring mad scientist foe of Superman who , in his Golden Age incarnation , resembled a balding , elderly man ."
    },
    {
        "answer": "Superman",
        "question": "Who was Luthor a recurring mad scientist foe of?",
        "sentence": "One hypothesis is that Nowak mistook Luthor for the Ultra - Humanite , a recurring mad scientist foe of Superman who , in his Golden Age incarnation , resembled a balding , elderly man ."
    },
    {
        "answer": "Superman",
        "question": "Who was Luthor a recurring mad scientist foe of?",
        "sentence": "One hypothesis is that Nowak mistook Luthor for the Ultra - Humanite , a recurring mad scientist foe of Superman who , in his Golden Age incarnation , resembled a balding , elderly man ."
    },
    {
        "answer": "Superman No",
        "question": "Luthor's design was confused with that of a bald henchman in what movie?",
        "sentence": "Other evidence suggests Luthor 's design was confused with that of a stockier , bald henchman in Superman No ."
    },
    {
        "answer": "bald henchman",
        "question": "What was Luthor's design confused with in Superman No?",
        "sentence": "Other evidence suggests Luthor 's design was confused with that of a stockier , bald henchman in Superman No ."
    },
    {
        "answer": "Superman No",
        "question": "What is the name of Luthor's next appearance?",
        "sentence": "4 ( Spring 1940 ) ; Luthor 's next appearance occurs in Superman No ."
    },
    {
        "answer": "10",
        "question": "When did Nowak depict him as significantly heavier?",
        "sentence": "10 ( May 1941 ) , in which Nowak depicted him as significantly heavier , with visible jowls ."
    },
    {
        "answer": "abrupt hair loss",
        "question": "What has been mentioned several times over the course of the character's history?",
        "sentence": "The character 's abrupt hair loss has been made reference to several times over the course of his history ."
    },
    {
        "answer": "Jerry Siegel",
        "question": "Who altered Luthor's backstory in 1960?",
        "sentence": "In 1960 , writer Jerry Siegel altered Luthor 's backstory to incorporate his hair loss into his origin ."
    },
    {
        "answer": "April 1945",
        "question": "When was the Superman comic strip pulled?",
        "sentence": "During World War II , the War Department asked for dailies of the Superman comic strip to be pulled in April 1945 which depicted Lex Luthor bombarding Superman with the radiation from a cyclotron , as it violated wartime voluntary censorship guidelines meant to help conceal the Manhattan Project ."
    },
    {
        "answer": "Lex Luthor",
        "question": "Who was depicted bombarding Superman with radiation from a cyclotron?",
        "sentence": "During World War II , the War Department asked for dailies of the Superman comic strip to be pulled in April 1945 which depicted Lex Luthor bombarding Superman with the radiation from a cyclotron , as it violated wartime voluntary censorship guidelines meant to help conceal the Manhattan Project ."
    },
    {
        "answer": "Luthor",
        "question": "Who vanished for a long time?",
        "sentence": "Luthor vanished for a long time , coming back in Superboy No ."
    },
    {
        "answer": "Superboy No",
        "question": "What was Luthor's last name?",
        "sentence": "Luthor vanished for a long time , coming back in Superboy No ."
    },
    {
        "answer": "Superboy",
        "question": "Who thinks he will be Superman by the time Luthor gets out?",
        "sentence": "In the last panel , Amazing Man is in jail and he tells Superboy he will regret it as sure as his name is Luthor and Superboy thinks that he will be Superman by the time Luthor gets out and that Luthor 's talents might make him an archenemy ."
    },
    {
        "answer": "Superman",
        "question": "Superboy thinks he will be what by the time Luthor gets out?",
        "sentence": "In the last panel , Amazing Man is in jail and he tells Superboy he will regret it as sure as his name is Luthor and Superboy thinks that he will be Superman by the time Luthor gets out and that Luthor 's talents might make him an archenemy ."
    },
    {
        "answer": "Adventure Comics No",
        "question": "Where was theversion of Luthor introduced?",
        "sentence": "Theversion of Luthor was introduced in Adventure Comics No ."
    },
    {
        "answer": "Adventure Comics No",
        "question": "Where was theversion of Luthor introduced?",
        "sentence": "Theversion of Luthor was introduced in Adventure Comics No ."
    },
    {
        "answer": "Adventure Comics No",
        "question": "Where was theversion of Luthor introduced?",
        "sentence": "Theversion of Luthor was introduced in Adventure Comics No ."
    },
    {
        "answer": "Adventure Comics No",
        "question": "Where was theversion of Luthor introduced?",
        "sentence": "Theversion of Luthor was introduced in Adventure Comics No ."
    },
    {
        "answer": "Adventure Comics No",
        "question": "Where was theversion of Luthor introduced?",
        "sentence": "Theversion of Luthor was introduced in Adventure Comics No ."
    },
    {
        "answer": "Adventure Comics No",
        "question": "Where was theversion of Luthor introduced?",
        "sentence": "Theversion of Luthor was introduced in Adventure Comics No ."
    }
]